<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mike Grouchy</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/feeds/02.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mikegrouchy.com/</id><updated>2013-02-21T20:25:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Using Johnny Cache with Heroku and Memcachier</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2013/02/using-johnny-cache-with-heroku-and-memcachier.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-21T20:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2013-02-21:blog/2013/02/using-johnny-cache-with-heroku-and-memcachier.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/jmoiron/johnny-cache"&gt;Johnny Cache&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty great caching framework for Django.
For most apps you can drop Johnny-cache in and depending on your Django project get
a good result right out of the box. If this sounds appealing check out the &lt;a href="http://pythonhosted.org/johnny-cache/"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;
for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent issue that I have run into is that a deploying a Django App on &lt;a href="http://heroku.com"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; with
Johnny Cache does not work out of the box with my &lt;a href="http://memcached.org/"&gt;Memcached&lt;/a&gt; service
of choice &lt;a href="http://www.memcachier.com/"&gt;Memcachier&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some investigation the issue here is that Johnny Cache doesn't support
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simple_Authentication_and_Security_Layer"&gt;SASL&lt;/a&gt; out of the box which is how the authentication for Memcachier works.
Memcachier reccomends using &lt;a href="https://github.com/jbalogh/django-pylibmc"&gt;django-pylibmc's&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://libmemcached.org/libMemcached.html"&gt;libmemcached&lt;/a&gt; backend to use its app.
Of course this isn't compatible with Johnny Cache out of the box either so what do you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Create your own SASL compatible backend for Johnny Cache&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a fairly straightforward problem to solve, we can just inherit from the
&lt;code&gt;PyLibMCCache&lt;/code&gt; backend from django-pylibmc and override its &lt;code&gt;_get_memcache_timeout&lt;/code&gt;
method with the one from Johnny Cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then update your django settings file to point at the new backend you have just
created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/mgrouchy/4956137.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure in your CACHES settings dict that you make sure you set BINARY to True
and you are off to the races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any questions? Feel free to ask in the comments or hit me up on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mgrouchy"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Announcing Django-Stronghold</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2013/02/announcing-django-stronghold.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-15T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2013-02-15:blog/2013/02/announcing-django-stronghold.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent much of last year trying to turn up my open source contributions
so I spent much of my time contributing to other peoples open source projects. Its
2013 and its a new year, so I am making a push to get some open source projects
that I have had in the pipe actually out there in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first of these is &lt;a href="http://github.com/mgrouchy/django-stronghold"&gt;django-stronghold&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a Django developer and
you have worked on a Django project of any size, you might have coded something
like this already which makes it the perfect target for open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stronghold defaults your Django project to private. This means that via
some middleware all your Django views become &lt;code&gt;login_required&lt;/code&gt;. Stronghold also
provides some mechanisims to make views public via a decorator or whitelisting
some of your url patterns. If this sounds useful to you &lt;a href="http://github.com/mgrouchy/django-stronghold"&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;. If you run into any issues please let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shout out to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/richardlblair"&gt;Richard Blair&lt;/a&gt; for help with this.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Introducing Python Jobs HQ</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2013/02/introducing-python-jobs-hq.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-14T10:35:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2013-02-14:blog/2013/02/introducing-python-jobs-hq.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you may know if you have read this blog, I am one of the curators for &lt;a href="http://pycoders.com"&gt;Pycoder's Weekly&lt;/a&gt;.
We have been working on a bunch of small projects to try to bring more value from Pycoder's
into the Python community. The first thing we have launched this year is &lt;a href="http://pythonjobshq.com"&gt;Python Jobs HQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pythonjobshq.com"&gt;Python Jobs HQ&lt;/a&gt; is a Job site we are running that is focused on
putting the best jobs in front of the best people. Jobs posted on the site are posted to
the &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/pycoders"&gt;@pycoders&lt;/a&gt; fast growing Twitter account and the Job Board
is advertised weekly in the newsletter. Already we have had great companies like &lt;a href="http://newsle.com"&gt;Newsle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://path.com"&gt;Path&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://datadoghq.com"&gt;Datadoghq&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://cyaninc.com"&gt;Cyan Inc&lt;/a&gt;. and others post with us. If you have a Python Job to post
for your company or if you are looking to find a new job as a Python Developer,
you should check out &lt;a href="http://pythonjobshq.com"&gt;Python Jobs HQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions feel free to reach out to me on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mgrouchy"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or email our &lt;a href="mailto:admin@pycoders.com"&gt;Pycoder's Email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Introducing Pycoders Weekly</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2012/02/introducing-pycoders-weekly.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-06T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2012-02-06:blog/2012/02/introducing-pycoders-weekly.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last couple of weeks &lt;a href="http://mahdiyusuf.com"&gt;Mahdi Yusuf&lt;/a&gt; and I have been talking
about the Python newsletter that we would want to recieve weekly. A curated
collection of the best Python news, articles and projects from around the internet
delivered to your inbox in a beautiful package weekly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of this talk has been &lt;a href="http://pycoders.com"&gt;Pycoders Weekly&lt;/a&gt;.
The first issue is set to drop on Friday, February 17th, we hope you like it.
&lt;a href="http://pycoders.com"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pycoders
Weekly" src="/static/images/2012/02/pycoders_weekly.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have created some content or run some project that you think should be
in &lt;a href="http://pycoders.com"&gt;Pycoders Weekly&lt;/a&gt; contact &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/myusuf3"&gt;Mahdi&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mgrouchy"&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; and let us know.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>