<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mike Grouchy</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/feeds/07.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mikegrouchy.com/</id><updated>2012-07-23T09:30:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Force websites to use SSL in Google Chrome</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2012/07/force-websites-to-use-ssl-in-google-chrome.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-23T09:30:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2012-07-23:blog/2012/07/force-websites-to-use-ssl-in-google-chrome.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw this tip in the comments over at &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; today
and I thought that this is a great alternative to force SSL for sites that don't have
it available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Step 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to Chrome's net internals dashboard by typing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;chrome://net-internals/&lt;/code&gt; into your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="net-internals" src="/static/images/2012/07/net-internals.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Step 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security"&gt;HSTS&lt;/a&gt;(HTTPS Strict Transport Security) Tab and you should see this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="hsts" src="/static/images/2012/07/hsts.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Step 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there its pretty easy, just type in the site you want to force to SSL and
you are done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="hsts" src="/static/images/2012/07/add-hsts-domain.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have any other Chrome security tips? Leave them in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>The Setup</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2012/07/the-setup.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-18T08:35:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2012-07-18:blog/2012/07/the-setup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is inspired by &lt;a href="http://www.mahdiyusuf.com/post/16687503726/the-setup"&gt;Mahdi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://usesthis.com/"&gt;The Setup&lt;/a&gt;. I had originally written a rather terrible post about my &lt;a href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/my-development-toolbox.html"&gt;development toolbox&lt;/a&gt; so I figured it was time to revisit this and get it right for people who care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a lot going on here, nothing fancy. Just macs, running OSX Lion. The hardware is a bit older, but I spend most of my time in a terminal, so I don't really notice so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Work:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2008 Aluminum Macbook, 4GB ram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magic Mouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standard Apple wired keyboard (I like having the numberpad and not having to be worried about batteries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;27" Cinema Display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all these things, I would have to say the cinema display is incredible. I don't normally use my laptop screen when it is connected to the cinema display to avoid &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Repetitive_strain_injury"&gt;RSI&lt;/a&gt; issues, however, when I do have it open its normally just for the &lt;a href="http://rd.io"&gt;rdio&lt;/a&gt; client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Home:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2010 iMac 21.5", 8GB Ram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magic Mouse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple wireless bluetooth keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't use this often, as it is the computer my &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/nicolegrouchy"&gt;wife&lt;/a&gt; uses primarily. I only tend to use it when I
don't feel like slogging around with my laptop at home, or I have left it at the &lt;a href="http://swixhq.com"&gt;office&lt;/a&gt; or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also taken to writing drafts for my blogposts using &lt;a href="http://gist.github.com"&gt;Github Gists&lt;/a&gt; with my &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/KLFZrw"&gt;1st Generation 32GB iPad&lt;/a&gt; and the apple bluetooth keyboard. I have found this to be a fantastic way to write a blogpost or a little code while out at a coffee shop or anywhere else when I am on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said earlier, I don't spend too much time outside the console, but when I do these are the things I couldn't live without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://manytricks.com/moom/"&gt;Moom&lt;/a&gt; - This is an awesome app, it allows you to tile windows in OSX, attach hotkeys to tiling commands and a bunch of other niceties that don't exist on OSX.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rd.io"&gt;rdio&lt;/a&gt; - As I mentioned earlier, I use rdio. I listen to music all the time while coding, or thinking or just about anything, so I have rdio going basically all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://giantcomet.com/flint"&gt;Flint&lt;/a&gt; - We use campfire for team chat in the office so I use flint for that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://chrome.google.com"&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt; - The web browser of champions, I pretty much use Chrome exclusively now and normally have way too many tabs open.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://skitch.com/"&gt;Skitch&lt;/a&gt; - I use skitch for taking screenshots on OSX it has really great support for simple editing and cropping of your screenshots that I would have a hard time switching to anything else. I dont use their server anymore for storage of my screenshots, I have a proxy set up using &lt;a href="http://heroku.com"&gt;heroku&lt;/a&gt; to send my screenshots to a Amazon S3 bucket. This is accomplished with &lt;a href="https://github.com/mgrouchy/s3itch"&gt;s3itch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://db.tt/Hc6Cqm1"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; -Dropbox is fantastic. I store all the git repos I am working on in Github and it has saved my butt a few times now. I can feel safe everything is backed up and even untracked files(in git) are being versioned, just incase I delete a untracked file I end up needing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alfredapp.com/"&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; - Alfred is an indispensable quick launcher app in the vein of &lt;a href="http://qsapp.com/"&gt;quicksilver&lt;/a&gt;. I spend most of my time with my hands off the mouse so I don't know what I would do without Alfred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://rescuetime.com/ref/161860"&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt; - I work pretty hard to try to stay productive and at the very least stay knowledgeable about where my time is going. RescueTime helps with that by tracking what I do on the computer every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Command Line Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The command line is where I spend most of my time, on OSX I don't use the terminal software that comes with OSX, I use &lt;a href="http://www.iterm2.com/"&gt;iTerm2&lt;/a&gt;. In that terminal I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zsh.org/"&gt;Zsh&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/"&gt;Oh-my-zsh&lt;/a&gt;, because as you know, &lt;a href=""&gt;Zsh is your friend&lt;/a&gt;, you can check out my .zshrc in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/mgrouchy/dotfiles"&gt;dotfiles repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vim.org/"&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; - The only text editor in my opinion. This is where I spend most of my time check out my &lt;a href="https://github.com/mgrouchy/vim"&gt;vimfiles&lt;/a&gt; for setup details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="vim screenshot" src="http://img.mikegrouchy.s3.amazonaws.com/1._ControlP_-_%28%7E%29_-_VIM_%28vim%29-20120628-111826.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tmux.sourceforge.net/"&gt;tmux&lt;/a&gt; - Tmux is great. Its a great alternative to gnu screen, highly configurable and looks great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="tmux screenshot" src="http://img.mikegrouchy.s3.amazonaws.com/1._tmux_%28tmux%29-20120628-111332.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bpython-interpreter.org/"&gt;bpython&lt;/a&gt; - bpython is improved interface to the Python interpreter. It supports syntax highlighting, autocomplete and a bunch of other useful features. I usually have bpython open all day every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bpython screenshot" src="http://img.mikegrouchy.s3.amazonaws.com/1._bpython_%28Python%29-20120628-111458.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On My desk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/L2qI4V"&gt;Natural Language Processing With Python&lt;/a&gt; - Steven Bird, Ewan Klein and Edward Loper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/KyjsLo"&gt;Javascript - The Definitive Guide&lt;/a&gt; - David Flanagan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/M3xogV"&gt;Expert Python Programming&lt;/a&gt; - Tarek Zaide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bunch of &lt;a href="http://pycoders.com"&gt;Pycoders&lt;/a&gt; stickers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pycoders Sickers!" src="http://mikegrouchy.com/media/images/2012/07/pycoders-stickers.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats about it. What does your setup look like?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Broken RSS Links Fixed</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2012/07/broken-rss-links-fixed.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-10T09:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2012-07-10:blog/2012/07/broken-rss-links-fixed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Darth Fail" src="/static/images/2012/07/darth-vader-epic-fail.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems my RSS feed has failed epically and none of the actual links to the blog
worked. Not too awesome for you RSS readers out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, that is fixed now. Thank you to the people who went through the
trouble to notify me of my broken RSS. Your help is much appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Setting up PyPy 1.9 on OSX</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2012/07/setting-up-pypy-19-on-osx.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-08T10:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2012-07-08:blog/2012/07/setting-up-pypy-19-on-osx.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="pypy" src="http://pypy.org/image/pypy-logo.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I had said before on &lt;a href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/setting-up-nginx-with-ssl-and-godaddy.html"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/great-django-test-talks.html"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, I sometimes use it as a way to record things I want to remember. This is one of those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have started a new project that uses PyPy and while there is documentation out there to get started, I find it useful to have it all in the same place and not spread around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is PyPy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyPy is Python interpreter and JIT compiler. The latest PyPy release PyPy 1.9, the one we are installing, is CPython 2.7.2 compatible. PyPy is focused on speed and 100% compatibility with the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CPython"&gt;CPython&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing PyPy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of options to install PyPy on OSX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can install using the &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/pypy/pypy/downloads/pypy-1.9-osx64.tar.bz2"&gt;binary&lt;/a&gt; from the PyPy website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can &lt;a href="http://pypy.org/download.html#building-from-source"&gt;build PyPy from source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can install using &lt;a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/"&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to manage my packages using Homebrew when thats an option, so I installed using Homebrew.
It was very easy to get setup just&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    brew install PyPy
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then follow any instructions in your terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should then see a symlink in your /usr/local/bin directory for PyPy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    ~ &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ls /usr/local/bin | grep pypy
    pypy
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And assuming you have homebrew setup correctly you should be able to type "pypy" in your terminal and get an interactive interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    ~ &amp;gt;&amp;gt; pypy
    Python 2.7.2 &lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;341e1e3821ff, Jun 07 2012, 15:42:54&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;PyPy 1.9.0 with GCC 4.2.1&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; on darwin
    Type &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;help&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;credits&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;license&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;more information.
    And now &lt;span class="k"&gt;for &lt;/span&gt;something completely different: &lt;span class="sb"&gt;``&lt;/span&gt;it&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;s beautiful: very rectangular&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;    and yellow&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you have gotten this far you have been successful at installing PyPy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, like any good &lt;a href="http://pycoders.com"&gt;pycoder&lt;/a&gt;, lets move on to getting PyPy setup inside a Virtualenv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting PyPy to work with Virtualenv or Virtualenvwrapper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily getting PyPy set up in a virtualenv is really easy, for virtualenv the command is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    virtualenv -p /usr/local/bin/pypy environmentname
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;for Virtualenvwrapper, its basically the same:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    mkvirtualenv -p /usr/local/bin/pypy environmentname
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the output of each of these commands you should see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    Running virtualenv with interpreter /usr/local/bin/pypy
    New pypy executable in testpypy2/bin/pypy
    Installing setuptools............done.
    Installing pip...............done.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now you can activate your environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In virtualenv:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; /path/to/your/virtualenv/bin/activate
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="http://www.doughellmann.com/projects/virtualenvwrapper/"&gt;virtualenvwrapper&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    workon environmentname
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And test your Python version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="codehilite"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    python --version
    Python 2.7.2 &lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;341e1e3821ff, Jun 07 2012, 15:42:54&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;PyPy 1.9.0 with GCC 4.2.1&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now you are good to get working on your Python project with PyPy. Happy hacking!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>SICP in Epub Format</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2010/07/sicp-in-epub-format.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-07-05T20:14:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2010-07-05:blog/2010/07/sicp-in-epub-format.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Awhile ago, I ran across a list of programming/algorithm/computer
science book reccomendations and on that list was &lt;a href="http://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/"&gt;Structure and Interpretation
of Computer Programs(SICP)&lt;/a&gt;. Ever since then it and a few other books have been
on the top of my &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; read list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been interested in learning lisp for quite awhile, I think its probably the
 &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; influence, lisp is often talked
 about there as Hacker News is written in a dialect of lisp authored by
 &lt;a href="http://paulgraham.com"&gt;Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://pdos.csail.mit.edu/~rtm/"&gt;Robert Morris&lt;/a&gt;
 called &lt;a href="http://arclanguage.org"&gt;Arc&lt;/a&gt;. So while in SICP the dialect of
 lisp is not Arc but Scheme, from its description and reviews I have read, SICP seems
 like it would be a great way to get started programming in lisp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why learn lisp you say? Certianly not to actually program in it professionally, I
 actually don't know anyone who programs in lisp for their job(Thats not to say there
 aren't lisp jobs out there). The reason to learn lisp is that by all accounts learning
 lisp is a transformative experience. I have consistently read and have had one of my
 very good friends tell me that learning to write lisp changes the way you think about
 programming and writing software. If nothing else that should make it worth the
 time and effort to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So back to SICP. I have been meaning to pick up a copy and start reading it for awhile
 but I had never got around to it. There is a web version but like a lot of people,
 I have a hard time reading from my computer screen, not because it hurts my eyes or
 anything like that, I think its just a matter of focus. There are so many things external
 to the book when you are reading it while sitting at your computer that it becomes tempting
 to multitask while reading. So today I was very excited to learn that &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ieure"&gt;Ian Eure&lt;/a&gt;
 created an epub copy of the book and its available on &lt;a href="http://github.com/ieure/sicp"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a perfect format for me, I can now load it onto my iphone(on stanza or ibooks)
 and read away while I spend my ~1.5 hours/day commuting on the bus back and forth to work.
 I usually try to get books in PDF form and just read them out of &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/referrals/NTE5Nzg0MTU5"&gt;dropbox&lt;/a&gt;,
 which is a good experience, but I would definately prefer epub as its easier to read.
 All in all this is a pretty big win for me and its certianly a great motivator to
 get me started reading SICP and learning Scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any books like SICP that you would reccomend? I'd love to get some suggestions,
 just leave a note in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>My Development Toolbox: An Introduction</title><link href="http://mikegrouchy.com/blog/2010/07/my-development-toolbox-an-introduction.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-07-04T18:14:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Mike Grouchy</name></author><id>tag:mikegrouchy.com,2010-07-04:blog/2010/07/my-development-toolbox-an-introduction.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately I have seen a bunch of posts where bloggers, developers, etc. talk about their
 current development environments and hardware. I really enjoy these posts because
 its always nice to see what tools other developers are using, so I thought I would
 chip in with a few blog posts of my own. In a couple of "My Toolbox" posts, I will
 talk about the hardware and software I use to do my work as Software Developer(currently
 doing mostly Python/Django work at &lt;a href="http://swixhq.com"&gt;SWIX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all the hardware I use in the office is pretty basic. I currently use a
 &lt;strong&gt;13.3-Inch MacBook Pro&lt;/strong&gt;, a pretty standard &lt;strong&gt;Dell 22-inch monitor&lt;/strong&gt;,
 standard &lt;strong&gt;Apple keyboard&lt;/strong&gt; and the amazing &lt;strong&gt;Apple Magic Mouse&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing fancy going on there, pretty standard hardware configuration and generally
 what everyone in the office currently uses as we all tend to work both in the office
 and from home from time to time. This hardware is essentially the perfect setup for
 the work that I do. Generally the apps that I use are pretty light and I find the
 13.3 inch Macbook Pro to be pretty zippy. Probably the only thing that would be a
 good upgrade would be from the 22-24 inch monitor to maybe 2-22 inch monitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does your setup look like? What kind of hardware do you use?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>